# Jens Johnson

## Software Engineer, Nike



📞 303-918-7742 🔀 jens.johnson@nike.com



github.com/jens-johnson



github.nike.com/jjo175



linkedin.com/in/jens-johnson-295072127



jens-johnson.com

### Summary

Software engineer at Nike who is passionate about using software development and design, technology, and project management to drive innovation and excellent team outputs. Areas of interest include data and analytics, user interfaces and experiences, application development, and cloud-driven architecture.

### Education

University of Oregon | Eugene, OR | September 2015 – June 2019 3.62 GPA, Dean's List Recipient, Summit Scholar

Computer and Information Science, B.S. Business Administration, B.S.

### **Experience**

Early-in-Career (EIC) Rotational Engineer Nike

Beaverton, OR | August 2019 - Present

Participating in the Early-in-Career (EIC) rotational engineering program in Nike Global Technology, rotating across several technology domains over the course of 18 months and engaging with a variety of technology functions across the organization through roles in software engineering and product ownership.

### Product Owner, Nike Music

Currently the acting product owner for the Nike Music. I oversee product management, evaluation, and growth strategies to enable the Nike Music experience in Nike retail stores across the globe, Nike-owned facilities, and for the Nike brand experience as a

- Coordinate multi-region, multi-store experience music strategy with partners across Nike Global Technology, Nike Brand, and Nike Direct, amongst others.
- Facilitate vendor relationships, integrations within the store technology landscape, and A/V strategies at scale.
- Assist in creating music and AV design approaches for different Nike concept doors, such as Houses of Innovation (HOI's) and Factory
- Helped design a strategy for store readiness using audio systems and alerting following closures due to Covid-19 in concert with Global Communications, Global Operations, and multiple other functional stakeholder groups.

### Software Engineer, PDH/API 360

Engineer with the PDH (Product Data Hub)/API 360 team in Nike Data and Analytics. Developed and maintained a variety of applications in the NDF (Nike Data Foundation) aimed at delivering dimensional and transactional data products to internal Nike consumers through several consumption patterns, including data lakes/warehouses/services and streaming, while meeting qualities of availability, reliability, consistency, and security.

- Developed data services on a hybrid cloud and serverless stack using a mix of AWS tools, including Lambda, Batch, and ECS.
- Refactored several legacy services, such as batch data refresh tools, to modernized solutions using Jenkins BMX pipelines, improving latency and error rates for applications.
- Led the development of a filtering implementation for a RESTful GraphQL interface over API 360's serverless application that allowed internal consumers to query across multiple Elastic Search clusters, providing robust and dynamic data access.
- Added functionality to logging and reporting services that enhanced the team's current Splunk/BI implementation, allowing for more visibility over application health.
- Helped implement an automated solution using version control hooks for verifying, consolidating, and deploying SQL scripts to a Snowflake data warehouse which allowed data engineers to automatically implement data transformations.

### **Experience**

## Software Engineering Intern

#### Nike

Beaverton, OR | June 2018 - August 2018

Software engineering intern with the Go-To Market Solutions (GTMS) organization as a participant in Nike Global technology's 11-week internship program. As a member of GTMS, I worked with the content foundation/digital storytelling team to develop and maintain software solutions for Nike.net, Nike's B2B sales platform.

- Created functionality to support core Nike.net infrastructure by developing Java Spring modules in Adobe Experience Manager (AEM).
- Worked closely with several cross-functional groups, including content authors and core engineers, to improve authoring tools and capabilities for Nike Marketing teams.
- Developed several content authoring features, including functionality to bypass seasonality and vendor filters when creating content, which provided marketing teams with a more holistic content creation pipeline.
- Participated in agile development practices as well as requirements gathering, testing and QA, and continuous integration for deployments.

## Project Manager Oregon Consulting Group

Eugene, OR | June 2017 - June 2019

Project manager with the Oregon Consulting Group, a student-led, professionally-managed organization, executing projects in market research, financial analysis, and business design and strategy for a variety of clients in the Pacific Northwest. Led teams of 4-5 consultants and managed client relationships, project execution, and organizational development.

- Developed an omnichannel e-commerce market entry and growth strategy for a consumer goods company that leveraged Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and Goodle Analytics to identify valuable market segments.
- Created a micro-financing analysis of the State of Oregon for a non-profit trust organization that provided insight into financing gaps for at-risk/under-privileged communities.
- Oversaw and aided the professional development of student consultants through coaching, skill enrichment, and continuous feedback.

# Student Consultant Oregon Consulting Group

Eugene, OR | December 2016 - June 2017

### **Organizations and Activities**

# 3<sup>rd</sup> Place Finalist **HACK72 Hackathon**

Beaverton, OR | August 2018

Participated in Nike's #HACK72 hackathon, creating a fully-functional iOS application with NFC, Amazon Lex, and SportsRadar integration to address the need for digital transformation in the consumer marketplace.

## Unit Leader Camp Kesem

Gresham, OR | January 2017 – June 2019

Led two units of children and counselors for Camp Kesem, an organization aimed at empowering and supporting children of parents with cancer; developed fundraising, training, and communication materials through year-around efforts.

# Wine Marketing Program Global Education Abroad

Siena, Italy | June - July 2017

Worked with Tuscan wine consortia to develop marketing plans, with a focus on the American import market, including a digitally-focused integrated marketing strategy for the Chianti Classico wine consortia.

### Skills and Proficiencies

#### Languages

#### Frameworks/Technologies

- PythonJavaJavaScript
- NodeJS, React, Express, VueMySQL, MongoDB,
- Automated Testing (Postman)
  Docker
  Bl (Splunk, Tableau)
- JavaScript PostgreSQL
  C/C++ GraphQL
  C# Spring, Spark
  Swift AWS (EC2, Lambda, Elastic
- Jupyter NotebooksUnity Engine

Microsoft Office Suite

- SaSS/LeSS Search, etc.)
  Ruby CI/CD (Jenkins, Circle CI)
- Sketch, Illustrator, Photoshop Google Analytics
- Human-Centered Design Team Development Public Speaking
- Other Competencies
- Agile/SAFe
- Mobile Application Development
- Data Analysis
- Project Management/Strategy
- UI/Mockups